Guide to the Archibald Macleish Collection
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Writings, 1915-76; Series I; 7.25; (17 boxes)
  - BOOKS
    - Plays
      - J.B.
        - Other papers
          - Photographs: Yale production, 1958 (Box 9, Folder 115)
          - Review: Yale production, 1958 Apr 23 (Box 9, Folder 116)
          - Review: Houghton Mifflin edition, 1958 (Box 9, Folder 117)
          - Reviews: Broadway production, 1958-59 (Box 9, Folder 118)
          - Reviews: English edition, 1959 Jul 31 (Box 9, Folder 119)
          - Reviews: sound recording, 1960 (Box 9, Folder 120)
          - Royalties, 1959-65 (Box 9, Folder 121)
          - Writings of MacLeish about J.B., 1959, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 122)
      - Panic
        - Notes, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 123)
        - Drafts of passages, holograph manuscript, corrected, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 124-25)
      - Scratch
        - Typescript, photocopy, 1971 (Box 10, Folder 126)
        - Publicity material, 1971 (Box 10, Folder 127)
      - Six Plays
        See: Oversize, Box 22, folder 454
      - This Music Crept by Me Upon the Waters
        - Holograph manuscript, corrected, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 128)
        - Holograph manuscript, corrected, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 129)
        - Final draft, holograph manuscript, corrected, 1952 Aug (Box 10, Folder 130)
        - Typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 131)
      - The Trojan Horse
        - Holograph manuscript, corrected, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 132)
    - Prose
      - The American Cause
        - Holograph manuscript, incomplete, corrected, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 133)
        - Typescript, incomplete, corrected, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 134)
        - Typescript, incomplete, corrected, [1940?] (Box 10, Folder 135)
      - A Continuing Journey
        - Outline, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 136)
        - Typescript and printed material, 1927-67, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 137-39)
        - Photocopies, corrected, 1943-65 (Box 10, Folder 140-41)
        - Photocopies, corrected, 1944-67, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 142-47)
        - Setting copy, corrected, with editorial markings, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 148-53)
        - Typescript and carbon, rejects and duplicates, 1944-67, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 154)
        - Typescript and carbon, rejects and duplicates, 1941-67, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 155-61)
        - Galley proofs, corrected, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 162)
        - Page proofs, with editorial markings, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 163)
        - Plate proofs, 1967 (Box 13, Folder 164)
      - The Eleanor Roosevelt Story
        See also: Oversize, Box 22, folder 455
        - Author's plan, typescript, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 165)
        - First draft, typescript, 1964 Nov 17-27 (Box 13, Folder 166)
          - Carbon, 1964 Nov 17-27 (Box 13, Folder 167)
        - Second draft, carbon, corrected, 1964 Dec 23 (Box 13, Folder 168)
        - Antigua draft, typescript, corrected, 1965 Jan 4-5 (Box 13, Folder 169)
          - Fragment, holograph manuscript, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 170)
        - End of manuscript, typescript, corrected (Box 13, Folder 171)
        - Setting typescript, corrected, with editorial markings, 1965 (Box 14, Folder 172)
        - Final script, typescript, photocopy, with editorial markings, 1965 Apr 8 (Box 14, Folder 173)
        - Repro proofs, 1965 (Box 14, Folder 174)
        - Galley proofs, corrected, 1965 (Box 14, Folder 175)
        - Galley proofs, with editorial markings, 1965 (Box 14, Folder 176)
        - Galley proofs, with editorial corrections, 1965 (Box 14, Folder 177)
        - Revised galley proofs, with editorial markings, 1965 (Box 14, Folder 178)
      - Poetry and Experience
        - Typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 179-81)
        - Typescript, corrected, miscellaneous pages, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 182)
        - Setting typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 183-86)
          - Index (Box 15, Folder 187)
        - Partial typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 188-90)
        - Galley proofs, corrected (with three leaves of typescript corrections), n.d. (Box 15, Folder 191)
        - Galley proofs, corrected, 1960 Jul 30 (Box 15, Folder 192)
        - Page proofs, corrected, 1960 (Box 15, Folder 193)
      - A Time to Speak: The Selected Prose of Archibald MacLeish
        - Review, 1941 May 4 (Box 15, Folder 194)
  - POETRY
    - Notebook, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 195)
    - "Actfive", n.d. (Box 16, Folder 196-97)
    - "Analogy," discarded draft, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 198)
    - "April in November", n.d. (Box 16, Folder 199)
    - "Arrival and Departure" (Box 16, Folder 200)
    - "At the University Memorial in the Year 1976" (Box 16, Folder 201)
    - "Autobiography", n.d. (Box 16, Folder 202)
    - "Beowulf Guest Poem", n.d. (Box 16, Folder 203)
    - "The Black Day: To the Memory of Lawrence Duggen," News Bulletin, 1949 Jan 1 (Box 16, Folder 204)
    - "Black Laughton", n.d. (Box 16, Folder 205)
    - "The Boatmen of Santorin", n.d. (Box 16, Folder 206)
    - "Boston," discarded draft (Box 16, Folder 207)
    - "Brooks Atkinson", n.d. (Box 16, Folder 208)
    - "Cartoon", 1930 (Box 16, Folder 209)
    - "Circular Lives", n.d. (Box 16, Folder 210)
    - "Colloquy for the States", n.d. (Box 16, Folder 211)
    - "Companions", n.d. (Box 16, Folder 212)
    - "Conquest of the Universe," discarded draft, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 213)
    - "Contemporary Chorus", n.d. (Box 16, Folder 214)
    - "Contemporary Portrait", n.d. (Box 16, Folder 215)
    - "Creator", n.d. (Box 16, Folder 216)
    - "Crow's Laughter", n.d. (Box 16, Folder 217)
    - "The Dead Lady of Tours", n.d. (Box 16, Folder 218)
    - "The Dichter as Doktor," discarded draft, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 219)
    - "Dr. Sigmund Freud Discovers the Sea Shell," discarded drafts (Box 16, Folder 220)
    - "The Ebb Tide," discarded drafts, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 221)
    - "For Amy Lowell", n.d. (Box 16, Folder 222)
    - "Frescoes for Mr. Rockefeller's City", n.d. (Box 16, Folder 223)
    - "Great Contemporary Discoveries", n.d. (Box 16, Folder 224)
    - "Hemingway", n.d. (Box 16, Folder 225)
    - "Hotel Breakfast", n.d. (Box 16, Folder 226)
    - "How the River Ninfa Runs Through the Ruined Town Beneath the Lime Quarry", n.d. (Box 16, Folder 227)
    - "Hurricane", n.d. (Box 16, Folder 228)
    - "Hypocrite Answer," discarded drafts, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 229)
    - "In My Thirtieth Year", n.d. (Box 16, Folder 230)
    - "Infiltration of the Universe," discarded draft, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 231)
    - "The Infinite Reason," discarded draft (Box 16, Folder 232)
    - "Journal of a Voyage," discarded draft, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 233)
    - "Letter in a Floating Bottle," discarded draft, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 234)
    - "Lilies", 1916 (Box 16, Folder 235)
    - "Limmerick, Limmerick" (to Geoffrey Parsons), n.d. (Box 16, Folder 236)
    - "Marie-Marthe in the Sunlight", n.d. (Box 16, Folder 237)
    - "Marijuana", n.d. (Box 16, Folder 238)
    - "Observations of P. Ovidius Naso on the Incidence of Sex in the Contemporary Novel", n.d. (Box 16, Folder 239)
    - "Old Man's Journey", n.d. (Box 16, Folder 240)
    - "Our Lady of Troy", n.d. (Box 16, Folder 241)
    - "The Peepers in Our Meadow", n.d. (Box 16, Folder 242)
    - "Physics of the Soul," discarded draft, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 243)
    - "Poem for a Festival of Art at the Boston Public Gardens", n.d. (Box 16, Folder 244)
    - "The Reef Fisher," discarded draft, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 245)
    - "The Sea Beyond the Flames" (Box 16, Folder 246)
    - "Seeing", n.d. (Box 16, Folder 247)
    - "The Ship in the Tomb", n.d. (Box 16, Folder 248)
    - "Ship of Fools," discarded draft, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 249)
    - "Ship's Log" (calligraphy copy by Keith Highet), n.d. (Box 16, Folder 250)
    - "Someone Else", n.d. (Box 16, Folder 251)
    - "Sound Track" (Box 16, Folder 252-53)
    - "Spring in These Hills", n.d. (Box 16, Folder 254)
    - "Tea" (restricted until 1991), 1915 (Box 16, Folder 255)
    - "Theory of Poetry," discarded drafts, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 256)
    - "Trailing Clouds of Glory Do We Come From Heaven That Is Our Home," discarded draft, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 257)
    - "Trees Growing", n.d. (Box 16, Folder 258)
    - "Tyrant of Syracuse", n.d. (Box 16, Folder 259)
    - "Wakened Early", n.d. (Box 16, Folder 260)
    - "Waking", n.d. (Box 16, Folder 261)
    - "What Riddle Asked the Sphinx", n.d. (Box 16, Folder 262)
    - "Where a Poet's From", n.d. (Box 16, Folder 263)
    - "The Wild Old Wicked Man", n.d. (Box 16, Folder 264)
    - "William Adams Delano", n.d. (Box 16, Folder 265)
    - "The Wisconsin-Nevada Axis," discarded draft, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 266)
    - "The Young Dead Soldiers," discarded draft, 1945 (Box 16, Folder 267)
    - Unidentified, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 268-70)
  - ARTICLES AND ESSAYS
    - Agee, James, Permit Me Voyage, with forward by Archibald MacLeish, typescript, corrected, 1934 (Box 17, Folder 271)
    - "As We Remember Him" (Stephen Vincent Benét), Saturday Review, 1943 Mar 27 (Box 17, Folder 272)
    - "The Beginning of Things," North American Review, 1924 Mar (Box 17, Folder 273)
    - [Girl in a Garden], holograph fragment, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 274)
    - Greece and Turkey, Aid for: speech, holograph manuscript, corrected (Box 17, Folder 275)
    - Harvard, speech at: typescript and holograph manuscript, corrected, 1967 (Box 17, Folder 276)
    - Hemingway, Ernest
      - "His Mirror Was Deeper," typescript, corrected, 1961 (Box 17, Folder 277)
      - Statement for the British Broadcasting Company, typescript, corrected, 1961 Jul 7 (Box 17, Folder 278)
      - Statement for the Voice of America, typescript, corrected, 1961 Jul 7 (Box 17, Folder 279)
    - Hilliard, Elias B., The Last Men of the Revolution, with forward by MacLeish, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 280)
    - "'J.B.' A Play in Verse: The Prologue"
      See also: Oversize, Box 22, folder 456
      - Holograph manuscript, corrected, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 281)
      - Typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 282)
      - Photocopy, corrected, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 283)
      - Galley proofs, corrected, 1956 (Box 17, Folder 284)
      - Saturday Review, 1956 Sep 1 (Box 17, Folder 285)
    - "The Librarian's Profession"
      - Typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 286)
      - Galley proofs, corrected, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 287)
    - "The Meaning of Peace"
      - Holograph manuscript, typescript, and mimeograph, 1943 (Box 17, Folder 288)
      - Printed version, 1943 (Box 17, Folder 289)
      - Fan mail, 1943-44 (Box 17, Folder 290-95)
    - "Mrs. Roosevelt: An Anniversary," holograph manuscript, corrected, 1963 (Box 17, Folder 296)
    - "The Muses' Sterner Laws" (remarks at Smith College), holograph manuscript and typescript, corrected, 1953 (Box 17, Folder 297)
    - National Book Award: remarks, holograph in hand of Ada MacLeish, 1953 (Box 17, Folder 298)
    - "The Next Harvard"
      - Typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 299)
      - Atlantic Monthly, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 300)
    - "The Next Philosophy," with Lawrence Mason, North American Review, 1923 May (Box 17, Folder 301)
    - "The Poet and America," The Carolina Quarterly, 1957 Winter (Box 17, Folder 302)
    - "Proclamation by the President of the United States" [not used], holograph manuscript, corrected, 1945 (Box 17, Folder 303)
    - Pulitzer Prize Dinner, Remarks at: typescript, corrected, 1959 (Box 17, Folder 304)
    - "Religion and the Requirements for a New Age of Reason," holograph manuscript, corrected, 1951 May (Box 17, Folder 305)
    - "Remarks at Yale," [October 7, 1960] typescript, corrected (Box 17, Folder 306)
    - Roosevelt Day Dinner, Remarks at January 26, 1951: holograph manuscript, corrected (Box 17, Folder 307)
    - "Trespass on a Monument" (written for New York Times in connection with Broadway production of J.B. ), typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 308)
    - UNESCO, speech at Wash[ington] University: holograph manuscript, corrected, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 309)
    - "The Venetian Grave"
      - Holograph manuscript, corrected, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 310)
      - Printed version, photocopy, [1976] (Box 17, Folder 311)
    - Wendell Willkie
      - Holograph manuscript, corrected, 1944 (Box 17, Folder 312)
      - Typescript, corrected, 1944 (Box 17, Folder 313)
    - "What Are the Fifties Like?," Smith Alumnae Quarterly, 1956 Summer (Box 17, Folder 314)
    - "Why Do We Teach Philosophy?," Atlantic Monthly, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 315)
    - Yale Class of 1915 Fifty-Fifth Reunion Dinner, Speech by MacLeish: typescript, corrected, 1970 (Box 17, Folder 316)
- Correspondence, 1916-80; Series II; 1; (2 boxes)
  Series II contains alphabetically arranged correspondence. Unidentified letters are placed at the end of the series.
  - Acheson, Alice, 1958 Mar 23 (Box 18, Folder 317)
  - Acheson, Dean, 1950 Jan 30 (Box 18, Folder 317)
  - Aiken, Conrad, 1926-27 (Box 18, Folder 318)
  - Anderson, Maxwell, 1959 Feb 2 (Box 18, Folder 319)
  - Angleton, James, 1940 (Box 18, Folder 320)
  - Babb, James T., 1937, 1960 (Box 18, Folder 321)
  - Baker, Mrs. George P., [1932?] (Box 18, Folder 322)
  - Bangs, Francis Hyde, 1942 (Box 18, Folder 323)
  - Bangs, Grace Allen, 1920-41 (Box 18, Folder 324)
  - Ben-Gurion, David, 1958 Jun 25 (Box 18, Folder 325)
  - Bergen, Francis, [1917] (Box 18, Folder 325)
  - Berssen, William, 1958 (Box 18, Folder 326)
  - Bishop, John Peale, 1926-32, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 327)
  - Bompiani, Valentino, 1960 (Box 18, Folder 328)
  - Bonney, Thérèse, 1961 Jul 25 (Box 18, Folder 329)
  - Boyd, Julian P., 1961-62 (Box 18, Folder 330-32)
  - Brewster, Kingman, 1976 (Box 18, Folder 333)
  - Bridsen, Geoffrey, 1957 (Box 18, Folder 334)
  - Brooks, Paul
    See: Houghton Mifflin Company, Box 18, folder 370
  - Buck, Bernard R., 1958 Jan 6 (Box 18, Folder 335)
  - Buttrick, George A., 1958 Mar 28 (Box 18, Folder 335)
  - Calder, Ritchie, 1958 Jan 16 (Box 18, Folder 336)
  - Campion, Richard, 1962 (Box 18, Folder 336)
  - Canfield, F. Curtis, 1956-58 (Box 18, Folder 337-38)
  - Choate, Elizabeth, 1920-27, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 339-42)
  - Ciardi, John, 1957-58 (Box 18, Folder 343)
  - Cisney, Marcella, 1958 Jan 24 (Box 18, Folder 344)
  - Cohen, Barbara, 1958 Jan 28 (Box 18, Folder 344)
  - Crawford, Cheryl, 1958 Mar 13 (Box 18, Folder 344)
  - Curtis Brown Ltd., 1957-58 (Box 18, Folder 345)
  - Davenport, Russell, 1936 Aug 3 (Box 18, Folder 346)
  - De la Mare, Walter, 1919 Jan 31 (Box 18, Folder 347)
  - De Liagre, Alfred (Delly), 1958-61, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 348-50)
  - Democratic Party, 1968 Oct (Box 18, Folder 351)
  - Dewar, Arthur, 1938 Dec 14 (Box 18, Folder 352)
  - Eliot, T. S., 1927-28, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 353)
  - Farrar & Rinehart, Inc., 1944 Aug 4 (Box 18, Folder 354)
  - Fitzgerald, F. Scott, c. 1930 (Box 18, Folder 355)
  - Galantière, Louis, 1928 Nov 15 (Box 18, Folder 356)
  - Gibson, Wilfrid Wilson, 1917 (Box 18, Folder 357)
  - Glazier, Sidney, 1964 Nov 23 (Box 18, Folder 358)
  - Gordis, Robert, 1958 Dec 9 (Box 18, Folder 358)
  - Gould, Mr., 1972 Mar 15 (Box 18, Folder 359)
  - Hambleton, T. Edward, 1957-62 (Box 18, Folder 360-61)
  - Harben, Robert, 1960 Jun 21 (Box 18, Folder 362)
  - Hesse, Eva, 1957-63, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 363-68)
  - Horton, Douglas, 1958 Apr 7 (Box 18, Folder 369)
  - Houghton Mifflin Company, 1952-58 (Box 18, Folder 370-73)
  - Houghton Mifflin Company, 1959-67 (Box 19, Folder 374-76)
  - Houghton, Norris
    See: Phoenix Theatre, Box 19, folder 408
  - Huett, Richard, 1958 Apr 2 (Box 19, Folder 377)
  - John W. Caldwell Little Theatre, 1958 Mar 21 (Box 19, Folder 378)
  - Joyce, James, 1927 (Box 19, Folder 379)
  - Kamlot, Robert, 1958 Mar 13 (Box 19, Folder 380)
  - Kazan, Elia (Gadg), 1958-59 (Box 19, Folder 381-83)
  - Lally, Francis J., 1959 Nov 10 (Box 19, Folder 384)
  - Lecky, William P., 1958 Mar 19 (Box 19, Folder 384)
  - Léger, Alexis, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 385)
  - Leigh, Robert D., 1946 Aug 8 (Box 19, Folder 386)
  - Lewis, Wilmarth S., 1941 May 10 (Box 19, Folder 387)
  - Lewis, Wyndham, 1927-30, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 388)
  - Liebert, Herman W., 1948, 1968 (Box 19, Folder 389)
  - Lister, Laurier, 1960-61 (Box 19, Folder 390-91)
  - Lowell, Amy, 1924 Feb 16 (Box 19, Folder 392)
  - Luce, Henry R., 1949 (Box 19, Folder 393)
  - Lustge[?], Mr., 1961 Jun 25 (Box 19, Folder 394)
  - Markel, Lester, 1959 Feb 3 (Box 19, Folder 395)
  - Marshall, Arthur Calder, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 395)
  - Masefield, John, 1916, 1920 (Box 19, Folder 396)
  - Mason, Lawrence, 1917-18, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 397)
  - Mizener, Arthur, 1937-38 (Box 19, Folder 398-99)
  - Monnier, Adrienne, 1927 Feb 24 (Box 19, Folder 400)
  - Moore, Marianne, 1927 Jul 21 (Box 19, Folder 401)
  - Morando, Sergio, 1960 (Box 19, Folder 401)
  - Mumford, L. Quincy, 1964 Oct 30 (Box 19, Folder 402)
  - Murdock, Kenneth R., 1959 Jan 12 (Box 19, Folder 402)
  - Nicolson, Harold, 1927 Jun 14 (Box 19, Folder 403)
  - Oenslager, Donald, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 404)
  - Ojetti, Paolo, Mrs., 1959 Jan 18 (Box 19, Folder 404)
  - Origo, Iris, 1957-58 (Box 19, Folder 405)
  - Page, Curtis C., 1958 Mar 11 (Box 19, Folder 406)
  - Peabody, Grace Allen
    See: Grace Allen Bangs, Box 18, folder 324
  - Perkins, Maxwell, 1930 Dec 30 (Box 19, Folder 407)
  - Phoenix Theatre, 1957-58 (Box 19, Folder 408)
    See also: T. Edward Hambleton, Box 18, folder 360
  - Pound, Ezra, 1967 Mar 2 (Box 19, Folder 409)
  - Probst, George E., 1958 Feb 24 (Box 19, Folder 410)
  - Quayle, Anthony, 1957-58 (Box 19, Folder 411)
  - Recordings for the Blind, Inc., 1961-69 (Box 19, Folder 412)
  - Rich, Philip
  - Robbins, Berenki L., 1958 Apr 3 (Box 19, Folder 413)
  - Robinson, Corinne Roosevelt, 1964, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 413)
  - Rodman, Selden, 1958 Apr 6 (Box 19, Folder 414)
  - Rubin, Louis D., Jr., 1958 Mar 8 (Box 19, Folder 414)
  - Die Salzburger Festspiele, 1958 (Box 19, Folder 415)
  - Sandburg, Carl, 1935, 1955, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 416)
  - Schüch, Karl, 1960 Aug 31 (Box 19, Folder 417)
  - Sedgwick, A. C., 1958 Jul 5 (Box 19, Folder 417)
  - Shawn, Ben, 1959 (Box 19, Folder 418)
  - Shumlin, Herman, 1956-57 (Box 19, Folder 419)
  - Siegel, Paul N., 1958 Dec 31 (Box 19, Folder 420)
  - Simmon, Henry E., 1962 (Box 19, Folder 420)
  - Sizer, Theodore, 1926, 1930 (Box 19, Folder 421)
  - Der Spiegel, 1958 Aug 29 (Box 19, Folder 422)
  - Squarzina, Luigi, 1958 (Box 19, Folder 422)
  - Strauss, Helen
    See: William Morris Agency, Box 19, folder 433
  - Suhrkamp Verlag, 1958-61 (Box 19, Folder 423)
  - Swiggett, Harold, 1944 Dec 12 (Box 19, Folder 424)
  - The Theatre Guild, 1958 May 27 (Box 19, Folder 425)
  - Tinker, Chauncey Brewster, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 426)
  - Untermeyer, Louis, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 427)
  - Van Dusen, Henry P., 1958-59 (Box 19, Folder 428)
  - Vosper, Margery, 1957-58 (Box 19, Folder 429)
  - Warburg, Frederic, 1958-59 (Box 19, Folder 430)
  - Weeks, Edward, 1958 Apr 4 (Box 19, Folder 430)
  - Wiedersheim, William A., 1980 (Box 19, Folder 431)
  - Wilder, Amos, 1958 Apr 1 (Box 19, Folder 432)
  - William Morris Agency, 1958-63 (Box 19, Folder 433)
  - Wilson, Roger B., 1976-77 (Box 19, Folder 434)
  - Yale University Library, 1961, 1965 (Box 19, Folder 435)
  - Yinger, Paul W., 1958 Apr 4 (Box 19, Folder 436)
  - Unidentified, 1922-60 (Box 19, Folder 437-38)
- Personal Papers, 1914-82; Series III; 1.75; (2 boxes)
  Personal Papers are alphabetically arranged, except for a scrapbook placed at the end of the series.
  - Brochure: Festival Mondial, 1958 (Box 20, Folder 439)
  - MacLeish, Archibald
    - Chamberlain, John, "Archibald MacLeish," Saturday Review, 1939 Jun 24 (Box 20, Folder 440)
    - Identity card, 1925 (Box 20, Folder 441)
    - Letter to editor: critical of MacLeish, 1942 Jun 20 (Box 20, Folder 442)
    - List of classics, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 443)
    - Obituary, 1982 Apr 21 (Box 20, Folder 444)
    - Undergraduate papers (Box 20, Folder 445)
    - The Yale Literary Magazine, issue devoted to MacLeish, 1941 Feb (Box 20, Folder 446)
  - MacLeish, Kenneth: death of, 1919 (Box 20, Folder 447)
  - Mizener, Arthur
    - "A MacLeish Exhibition," typescript, 1938 (Box 20, Folder 448)
    - A Catalog of the First Editions of Archibald MacLeish, 1938 (Box 20, Folder 449)
  - Unidentified poem, 1922 (Box 20, Folder 450)
  - Scrapbook: letters and verses of Archibald MacLeish, collected by Francis Hyde Bangs, 1914-24 (Box 21, Folder 451)
  - RESTRICTED UNTIL 1991
- Oversize, 1936-80; 2; (1 box)
  Box 22 holds five oversize items from Series I.
  - POETRY
    - Public Speech; Poems by Archibald MacLeish
      - Proofs, 1936 (Box 22, Folder 452)
  - PLAYS
    - J.B.
      - Articles about, 1959 (Box 22, Folder 453)
    - Six Plays
      - Galley proofs, corrected, 1980 (Box 22, Folder 454)
  - PROSE
    - The Eleanor Roosevelt Story, first draft, typescript, 1964 Nov 17-27 (Box 22, Folder 455)
  - ARTICLES AND ESSAYS
    - "J.B.," proofs for article in Saturday Review, 1956 (Box 22, Folder 456)
- Restricted Fragile Papers
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restricted fragile material. Reference surrogates have been substituted in the main files. For further information consult the appropriate curator.
  - Box 1, folder 11 (Box 23, Folder 457)
  - Box 2, folder 21 (Box 23, Folder 458)
  - Box 2, folder 26 (Box 23, Folder 459)
  - Box 2, folder 27 (Box 23, Folder 460)
  - Box 2, folder 28 (Box 23, Folder 461)
  - Box 2, folder 29 (Box 23, Folder 462)
  - Box 3, folder 37 (Box 23, Folder 463)
  - Box 3, folder 46 (Box 23, Folder 464)
  - Box 3, folder 48 (Box 23, Folder 465)
  - Box 4, folder 58 (Box 23, Folder 466)
  - Box 4, folder 60 (Box 23, Folder 467)
  - Box 6, folder 69 (Box 23, Folder 468)
  - Box 6, folder 70 (Box 23, Folder 469)
  - Box 6, folder 71 (Box 23, Folder 470)
  - Box 6, folder 72 (Box 23, Folder 471)
  - Box 6, folder 76 (Box 23, Folder 472)
  - Box 6, folder 77 (Box 23, Folder 473)
  - Box 6, folder 78 (Box 23, Folder 474)
  - Box 6, folder 79 (Box 23, Folder 475)
  - Box 9, folders 108-09, 113 (Box 23, Folder 476)
  - Box 9, folder 116-17 (Box 23, Folder 477)
  - Box 9, folder 118 (Box 23, Folder 478)
  - Box 9, folders 119-20, 122 (Box 23, Folder 479)
  - Box 10, folder 128 (Box 23, Folder 480)
  - Box 10, folder 129 (Box 23, Folder 481)
  - Box 10, folder 130 (Box 23, Folder 482)
  - Box 10, folder 132 (Box 23, Folder 483)
  - Box 10, folder 136 (Box 23, Folder 484)
  - Box 10, folder 137 (Box 23, Folder 485)
  - Box 10, folder 139 (Box 23, Folder 487)
  - Box 13, folder 166 (Box 24, Folder 488)
  - Box 13, folder 167 (Box 24, Folder 489)
  - Box 13, folder 170 (Box 24, Folder 490)
  - Box 13, folder 171 (Box 24, Folder 491)
  - Box 16, folder 196 (Box 24, Folder 492)
  - Box 16, folders 198, 200, 209, 216, 220-21 (Box 24, Folder 493)
  - Box 16, folders 224, 229-33, 236 (Box 24, Folder 494)
  - Box 16, folders 243-46, 249, 266 (Box 24, Folder 495)
  - Box 17, folder 275 (Box 24, Folder 496)
  - Box 17, folder 281 (Box 24, Folder 497)
  - Box 17, folder 283 (Box 24, Folder 498)
  - Box 17, folder 288 (Box 24, Folder 499)
  - Box 17, folder 297 (Box 24, Folder 500)
  - Box 17, folder 303 (Box 24, Folder 501)
  - Box 17, folder 309 (Box 24, Folder 502)
  - Box 18, folders 319, 340-42 (Box 24, Folder 503)
  - Box 18, folders 345, 360, 362-64, 367, 371-72 (Box 24, Folder 504)
  - Box 19, folders 378, 382-83 (Box 24, Folder 505)
  - Box 19, folders 386, 392, 423, 433 (Box 24, Folder 506)
  - Box 19, folders 435, 438 (Box 24, Folder 507)